Sankt Jeder, Giad Federacy
The Festival of the Holy Birth is next week,
and the whole city's getting ready!
December 18th, Stellar Year 2148
Today we'll show you just
how much fun everyone's having!
This is a special ornament set
you can get only at this market.
It's so cute, isn't it?
It's kind of expensive!
I want it, though.
Oh, fine! I'll take it!
What?
Thank you!
Theresa, where's Shinei?
I'm tired!
Really?
You're really tough.
You loaded that fridge
all by yourself, right?
Oh, that's easy,
if you know the trick.
No, no.
But that delivery to the seventh floor
with no elevator yesterday was really rough, right?
It was a three-ring circus
filled with fun and excitement.
What?
Want to go to that café?
Okay!
Where are we going now?
Hmm... Maybe try on some clothes?
Okay!
You've got a nice touch.
Thank you.
Cooking Class
Hey, you only ever learned
to make desserts, right, Anju?
You'll want to learn to do normal cooking,
or you'll have problems in the future.
Future?
When you cook for your kids,
for example.
Kids? No way!
Imperial Capital Central Library
There he is!
He's always so cool!
Hi, there!
H-Hey!
Nina, when someone does something for you
or lets you have something, say "thank you."
Sorry, my sister was very rude.
No, it's fine.
I wasn't reading it.
It's not fine!
You need to have them learn
at a young age.
Come on.
Thank you...
Hey!
Oh jeez... that girl.
Thanks.
Sorry to get you involved in that.
No, it must be rough
being a big brother.
I don't know where she got it from,
but she's really shy.
Um... This may be rude,
but you're here a lot
at this time of day.
Don't you have school?
What about you?
If you see me a lot,
that means you're here, too.
Oh, yeah.
I don't go to school.
I can't.
We're not that wealthy.
Sorry for just talking
to you out of nowhere.
I'm Eugene Rantz.
Nice to meet you.
Shinei Nouzen.
Frederica Rosenfort!
Nina Rantz.
What are you doing?
I read her a book,
and she took a liking to me.
It was a story for little kids,
with lots of princes and princesses!
I'll read the rest some other time.
Okay!
Sorry.
Your little sister?
Not a chance.
Shinei!
You're not doing anything, right?
Come with me.
It's a little early, but why not get it
for her as a festival present?
I'll give you a discount,
since your little sister's so cute.
Not a chance.
Big brother!
I want it!
I... I... want it...
You're more gullible than you look.
Where did you learn
how to do that stuff?
I want to go home early tomorrow,
so I'll stay a little later tonight.
It's the Eve of the Holy Birth tomorrow.
The Republic has a tradition
of exchanging presents, too.
Presents, huh?
What would be good, I wonder...
They've been here a month,
and they've all found friends
and things to do.
They're fitting in well.
Yes, it's a good sign
that they've made friends.
They'll be fine.
We're going to have to find a real path
for them to take in life, once spring comes around.
I know it's an awful thing to ask.
You've gone as far as you can go.
You've taken us with you.
So you should be able to forget about us.
But knowing that...
It still hurts.
Staying here hurts.
I'm dead. I want to go home.
So... Shin.
Our Reaper...
Please, save us.
Shin!
I know the sunlight's nice and warm,
but the librarians will get mad at you for sleeping!
December 24th, Stellar Year 2148
Did you stay up too late?
No...
It's about time.
Want to go see?
What?
The military's Holy Birth Festival Eve Parade!
This year it's the Western Theater's
24th Mechanized Infantry Division,
so we should be able to see the latest
model of third-generation Vánagandrs!
Oh, are you not interested?
No, you just don't seem like
somebody who would care about that.
I'm joining the service.
I volunteered for the Mechanized Infantry.
So I wanted to see them.
I thought you were the same.
You were looking at military documents
yesterday and the day before.
I thought you were trying to get
into the Special Officer's School, too.
This place is peaceful,
but they're fighting at the border.
And we don't know
when the war will come here.
If there's something I can do
to prevent that,
to protect my little sister
and this town, I want to do it...
And someday, I want my sister
to see the ocean.
So I need this war to end.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll be off.
Come if you're curious.
I've rested too long.
December 24th, Stellar Year 2148
There you are!
You said you were going
to Republic Plaza,
so I thought you might be here.
What?
I want your help with something.
I need to carry some things,
and I can't do it all on my own.
Sure, sure. Need anyone else?
Shin's probably free.
Shin—
These things sure are "convenient,"
aren't they?
Even though you have
to carry them around everywhere,
and they don't work
if the other person turns them off,
and you have to punch in the number
each time or register it...
You preferred the implants?
It's weird how the Federacy
wanted those things.
I know it's odd to say this
after we used them for so long,
but we know basically nothing about them.
Well, they're probably useful
on the battlefield.
These things get jammed easily, I guess.
As for the Juggernauts,
I don't know what they expect to learn
from looking at those walking coffins.
There wasn't anything I wanted
to take from them, though.
Same.
He's not answering!
You know... Shin wanted
his scarf and pistol back.
Ernst ended up holding on to the pistol.
It's the pistol he used to end everyone's lives.
Shin never let anyone else do that.
I'm sure he had to,
because of the voices,
but I don't think it would kill him
to take it easier.
There were probably times when
being trapped by it helped him survive.
In a way, it kept him alive.
Maybe having the goal of killing his brother
kept him here with us.
Without that, now he's...
This place, Republic Plaza,
is where the Republic's embassy was.
I didn't know that when I came here.
Maybe I'm still trapped, too.
What about you, Anju?
You were supposed to die on that
battlefield, but you're still alive.
They want us to think about our futures.
Have you decided on yours?
I thought about it a lot,
but it's the same.
The things I think
I should be doing...
You're asking me now?
Isn't it too late for that?
Yeah.
Anyway!
Oh, right.
Come on, Shin!
Wow! The Vánagandrs are huge!
How do you drive one of those?
I'd love to give it a try.
How about this one?
I'm sure you'd look great in it!
If you wait till next week,
it'll be 20% off!
Next week...
Yup, yup!
I don't really know...
Come back if you change your mind!
Okay...
Come in!
Hey, I haven't seen you in a while!
What are you looking for today?
Want to try on some of our new stuff?
You'll love it!
What's wrong?
Raiden, welcome back.
Where's Theresa?
She went shopping
and hasn't come back.
Nobody's here?
So—
I'm really hungry!
I'm—
Just wait.
It's delicious!
You have my gratitude, Raiden!
Right, right.
Weren't you going drinking
with your work buddies today?
Oh...
I canceled.
You're lucky I was the one
who came home early.
If it were Shin, things would have
turned out quite differently.
What... so Shinei is a bad cook?
Not bad, but he doesn't care,
and it shows.
He only cares about fighting.
I see.
Sounds like a man who dedicated
everything to killing his brother.
How did you know about Shin's brother?
Well...
Eat your carrots, too.
How did you get in here
without making any noise?
Habit.
"Habit"?!
What's all this stuff?
Stop it! It scares me!
Just get used to it,
and it won't be a problem.
We went shopping with Theresa,
and the car broke down.
And since there was a lot to carry...
We looked.
We called him.
Welcome home.
Thank you, everyone.
I wasn't doing anything anyway.
You should've just asked
from the start.
I'm a servant here. I can't let
the master's children carry my things.
No, he's not our dad.
Oh, welcome home, Kurena.
Yeah...
What's wrong?
Um, well...
I... think I've seen
everything I need to see!
You've had enough?
Yeah...
Let's go back...
to where we belong!
Why?
"Why?"
We're sorry for being suspicious at first.
This is a good place.
So we stayed here a little too long.
We've had our rest.
And want to keep going.
So we're going back.
But why go back to the battlefield?
We said we wanted to from the start.
Yes, but...
We were lucky, that's all.
If we use that as an excuse
to stay here,
what can we say to those
who died fighting until the end?
We can't pretend
to be at peace when we're not.
Even if we're going to die either way,
we can choose how.
If we're going to die someday,
we will fight till the end.
That's the life we chose.
Please don't take that from us.
That's not true!
It's not!
You made it here because
you fought to the end!
You have the right
to enjoy your reward!
That's what your comrades would want!
It's not something to be ashamed of!
Silence, Ernst.
They've finally escaped
a cage of oppression.
Now you're going to trap them
in a cage of pity?
You're not so stupid to miss
that you'd be the same as the Republic.
They're not young, ignorant children.
If they want to go, let them go.
And it wouldn't do to say you're going on ahead,
only to have someone else go first.
All right.
But on one condition.
You need to go through the Special Officer's
Training School and become officers.
Otherwise, no.
When you leave the service, officers will have
more opportunities than enlisted soldiers.
I want you to have as many choices available
to you as possible when this war is over.
"When the war is over"?
I never thought about that.
This war will end someday.
If you want to fight until the end,
you need to think about
what'll happen when it's over.
You should be able to accept that.
I understand that you've got nothing
but your pride to keep you together.
But that's no way for a
complete human being to live.
It's blood and soil that
make a person who they are.
If you have neither, and try to define yourself
just by who you personally are,
when you lose sight of that,
you'll quickly fall apart.
Never forget that.
Who are you talking to, princess?
I'm not a princess.
My true name is Augusta Frederica Adel-Adler.
The last Empress of the Empire of Giad,
who ordered the Legion to invade
the rest of the continent ten years ago.
I am one of those who took your families
and your home from you.
If there's anything you want
to say to me, go ahead.
I don't know if you're
the last empress or whatever,
but it was the Republic
who took everything from us.
We're not going
to suddenly forget that now.
Don't insult us.
Also, how old were you ten years ago?
I'm sorry.
I admire your pride,
so let me make a request of you Eighty-Six.
January 7th, Stellar Year 2149
If you're going back to the battlefield,
take me with you!
And help me destroy my knight's ghost!
He was taken by the Legion?
Yes. The Legion who attacked you
just before you reached this country.
How do you know?
The power of the blood
I inherited allows me
to see glimpses of the present
and past of those I meet.
The wound your brother gave
you hurt, didn't it?
I'm sorry. I saw.
But seeing is all I can do!
I can't save Kiriya alone!
So please... help me!
Like the brother you saved,
and who saved you in turn...
Save my knight!
Shin, hurry up!
Have a good trip.
We're off!
"Glad to be here."